{
    "id": "0235f11899784affabfdaff1bee86c8a",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I ................................",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "won't go",
                "wouldn't go",
                "wouldn't have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2620a55decfc4f2baf17c2322422ac48"
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she would be happy if she ................................ more money.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8b5d6bc78524432a8aa8d22588e8ffbc"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you leave now, you ............................... the bus.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will catch",
                "would catch",
                "could catch"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d6cd5d2d81e949d4b22dd7381daa809f"
        },
        {
            "question": "My mother told me that if I had passed the test, she ....................................... me a bike.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will buy",
                "would buy",
                "would have bought"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "eaa7dab11cfb4e10924b105a4fd15cd4"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were rich, I ............................... more time on traveling.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will spend",
                "would spend",
                "would have spent"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0236a4ba0e674561b053ec8da695151a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had come on time, he ................................... mad.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not go",
                "would not go",
                "would not have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "861a3c7e10a847479d422aa3d6ff090c"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had apologized, they ................................... any further actions against you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will not take",
                "would not take",
                "would not have taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6235ad4d8b9c4399838aad701fd4b283"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ................................ early, you could meet her.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "arrived",
                "had arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "273b3c20ed2d41d49881ab204728da99"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ................................ the money, I would have admitted it.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "take",
                "took",
                "had taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "83e6308a952e4cd3a15cb6bc5e0271c8"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ............................... more politely, she would lend you her car.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "asked",
                "ask",
                "had asked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2d87cec2fe5346d380dca40e4b71d51b"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you love me, I .................................. you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will love",
                "would love",
                "would have loved"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "feae0058a1fe429899fcb19e2f04ec23"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ........................................... Spanish at university, she could work as a translator.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "learn",
                "learned",
                "had learned"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "dcf862add76a49d3b2e5977a02ccab74"
        }
    ]
}